ALLISON PITTMAN

Denver, CO

pittman.ally@gmail.com

(703) 350-2792

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/allison-pittman

GitHub: https://github.com/avyrie

Software Engineer with a BS in Biology and 11 years of customer service, administration, and sales experience. As a hard-working self-starter with extreme attention to detail, I always strive to perform above and beyond what is asked of me in an enthusiastic manner. I am a customer-oriented professional who excels at analyzing and resolving issues while displaying compassion and empathy. I pride myself on being very teachable and adaptive to each new roll I undertake in my personal and professional career.

SKILLS & TOOLS

Technical Knowledge: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python, Node.js, Express, EJS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Django, React

Operating Systems: Windows, Mac IOS

Software Applications: Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint), Salesforce, Mailchimp, 123Pet, AVImark Veterinary Software, Hosted Suite, Evo, HubSpot, Morningstar, Lightspeed, Weebly, Postman, Lucidchart.

Social Media Platforms: Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, Tumblr

General Skills: Payroll, Service Sales, New Employee Training, Invoicing/General Accounting, Data Entry, Client Resolution, Retail Management, Retail Sales, Veterinary Assistance, Inventory Control, Call Center Work, Appointment Scheduling, Reception, Typing, Customer Service

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Apprentice

General Assembly - Denver, CO (remote), June 8, 2020 to August 30, 2020

General Assembly is an educational company specializing in technological bootcamps. My time in their Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp was spent participating in a remote classroom environment Monday through Friday where we engaged in lectures and hands-on assignments.

- Received training in front-end and back-end software development, specifically in HTML5, CSS3, JS, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, React, Django, and Python
- Created multiple solo and team projects including everything from small-scale games to full-stack websites applications.

Inventory Specialist

Luke & Company Fine Pet Supply & Outfitters - Denver, CO, October 2019 to May 2020

Luke & Co. is a locally-owned pet supply boutique specializing in health and wellness especially concerning diet wellness. As the inventory specialist I was responsible for tasks ranging from physically stocking inventory to creating relationships with company reps in order to invite in new items.

- Populated and confirmed large weekly orders using Lightspeed that routinely exceeded \$10,000 through major vendors and direct-to-order companies.
- Maintained accurate inventory levels for over 15,000 SKU's using virtual spreadsheets and physical stock checks.
- · Created relationships with various company reps and oversaw acquisition of new inventory.
- Assisted clients with information and suggestions based on unique needs about the company's products and services.

Area Center Coordinator

Metro Offices - Northern Virginia, February 2019 to September 2019

Metro Offices is a woman-owned successful "small business" specializing in physical and virtual shared and private work spaces. My responsibilities as an Area Center Coordinator required me to travel to three to four different centers in the area per week in order to assist each center with various services while maintaining a professional appearance and demeanor.

- Assisted clients with a myriad of questions and requests including equipment loans, meeting room booking, center tours, service quotes, and more.
- Maintained open communication with other centers within the company to ensure clients were taken care of regardless of location.
- Screened/directed incoming phone calls in a manner specific to each company receiving answering service with a pleasant demeanor and accurate transfers.
- Organized and hosted several events at several centers celebrating various holidays and appreciation days.

Manager/Pet Sitter

Independent Pet Sitting - Northern Virginia, January 2014 to September 2019

My position maintaining a small-scale pet sitting business required a high level of organization concerning time management, schedule maintenance, and paperwork filing as well as individually-specialized pet care.

- Created a contract containing relevant information and liability release to be presented to new clients.
- Built a solid client base through personal connections and client referrals with several clients requesting repeat services over several years.
- Individually managed appointment scheduling/finances/billing and continued to provide top-notch service while maintaining positions at day job.

Assistant Manager

Bark 'N Bubbles - Fairfax, VA, 2014 to September 2019

Bark 'N Bubbles is a woman and locally-owned business specializing in full and self-service dog and cat grooming. As an Assistant Manager with a small, family-run business, an extreme amount of emphasis was targeted towards a positive customer experience and satisfaction.

- Ensured each customer receives an exceptional experience and effectively resolved any issues to their satisfaction.
- Oversaw employee accuracy regarding quotes given and appointments made as well as training for new employees.
- Assisted owner of company with hiring, product selection/ordering, payroll, and day-to-day business operations ranging from maintaining a clean and orderly space to overseeing service execution.

Data Entry/Research Specialist

CyberSecJobs - Northern Virginia, June 2018 to January 2019

CyberSec Jobs is a recruiting company focused on placing individuals with high security clearance in suitable employment positions. My role with this company involved acquiring contact information of talent acquisition managers and sending e-mail blasts about future recruiting events.

- Researched and collected contact information relevant to potential clients.
- Organized and deployed email campaigns to 100+ contacts using virtual spreadsheets and MailChimp.
- Maintained detailed data logs of client communication using Salesforce.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive (SEI) Program

General Assembly - Denver, CO, June 8, 2020 to August 31, 2020

Bachelor's in Biology

George Mason University - Fairfax, VA August 2014 to December 2017

CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES

Notary Public

Virginia, Valid June 2019 to September 2023